{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Any system that is not at equilibrium", "opta": "is thermodynamically unstable, although it may be kinetically stable", "optb": "is kinetically unstable, although it may be thermodynamically stable", "optc": "is rushing toward equilibrium at a very rapid rate", "optd": "requires an enzyme to reach equilibrium", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The element neon (Ne) has eight electrons in its outermost electron shell. How many covalent bonds will Ne readily form?", "opta": "None", "optb": "One", "optc": "Two", "optd": "Four", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following functional groups would make a carbon-based compound the least polar?", "opta": "Phosphate", "optb": "Methyl", "optc": "Carboxyl", "optd": "Amino", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not true about a photon?", "opta": "It is a packet of light energy", "optb": "The shorter the wavelength, the greater the energy of the photons", "optc": "It is trapped by photosynthetic unit", "optd": "It donates electron to reduce carbon dioxide to glucose", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the ends of the following polysaccharide are pulled, which one would stretch the most?", "opta": "Glycogen", "optb": "Starch", "optc": "Cellulose", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following elements is likely to form the least polar covalent bond with hydrogen?", "opta": "Nitrogen", "optb": "Oxygen", "optc": "Carbon", "optd": "Phosphorus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The mitochondria were known in the nineteenth century to be osmotically active on the basis of evidence that", "opta": "the mitochondrial matrix is hypotonic to the cellular cytoplasm", "optb": "the mitochondrial matrix is hypertonic to the cellular cytoplasm", "optc": "mitochondria were derived from a symbiotic bacterium", "optd": "mitochondria are surrounded by a semi permeable membrane", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Mitochondria can be expected most numerous in", "opta": "green cells", "optb": "red blood cells", "optc": "muscle cells", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why do some redox reactions in cells result in the transfer of electrons from a reductant with a higher standard redox potential to an oxidant with a lower standard redox potential?", "opta": "Redox potentials are defined under standard conditions, and cellular conditions are typically not standard conditions", "optb": "The rules governing oxidation and reduction apply only in vitro, and not in vivo", "optc": "Electrons always go from reductants with high redox potentials to oxidants with low redox potentials", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Lysosomes are associated with", "opta": "photosynthesis", "optb": "respiration", "optc": "storage", "optd": "digestion", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which cell type is likely to have the most mitochondria?", "opta": "Fast-twitch muscle", "optb": "Slow-twitch muscle", "optc": "Liver cells", "optd": "Adipose cells", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Tonoplast is a membrane around", "opta": "cytoplasm", "optb": "vacuole", "optc": "nucleus", "optd": "mitochondria", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A cell without cell wall is called", "opta": "apoplast", "optb": "protoplast", "optc": "symplast", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chemical energy is supplied to eukaryotic cells by", "opta": "chloroplasts and golgi complexes", "optb": "mitochondria and ribosomes", "optc": "mitochondria only", "optd": "mitochondria and chloroplasts", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which part of a plant contains the male sex cell?", "opta": "Ova", "optb": "Style", "optc": "Stamen", "optd": "Pollen", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\"The universe tends towards maximum disorder\" is stated by", "opta": "first law of thermodynamics", "optb": "second law of thermodynamics", "optc": "third law of thermodynamics", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Water content of active protoplasm is", "opta": "10%", "optb": "40%", "optc": "70%", "optd": "90%", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an electron carrier class in the electron transport chain?", "opta": "Flavoproteins", "optb": "Cytochromes", "optc": "Iron - sulfur proteins", "optd": "Cytochrome c oxidase", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the source of free energy (\u0394G) for moving protons out of mitochondria against their concentration and electrical gradients?", "opta": "Glycolysis", "optb": "Creatine phosphate", "optc": "The redox reactions of electron transport", "optd": "ATP", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cellular organelle associated with photosynthesis is the", "opta": "golgi complex", "optb": "mitochondrion", "optc": "lysosome", "optd": "chloroplast", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cellular metabolism is an example of", "opta": "equilibrium metabolism", "optb": "steady-state metabolism", "optc": "a series of reactions occurring under standard conditions", "optd": "a series of reactions that defy the second law of thermodynamics", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following experimental results does not support Mitchell's chemiosmosis theory?", "opta": "Electron transport in isolated mitochondria was shown to result in acidification of the medium", "optb": "Addition of dinitrophenol to isolated mitochondria was shown to inhibit electron transport, but had no effect on ATP synthesis", "optc": "Addition of dinitrophenol to isolated mitochondria during electron transport was shown to inhibit acidification of the medium", "optd": "An artificial proton gradient across the inner mitochondrial membrane drives ATP synthesis in the absence of electron transport", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Both plant and animal cell possess", "opta": "cell walls", "optb": "mitochondria", "optc": "central vacuoles", "optd": "chloroplast", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cellular organelle associated with secretion is the", "opta": "golgi complex", "optb": "mitochondrion", "optc": "ribosome", "optd": "lysosome", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements about mitochondrial proteins is true?", "opta": "All mitochondrial proteins are coded for and synthesized in the mitochondria", "optb": "Some mitochondrial proteins are coded for and synthesized in the mitochondria and others", "optc": "All mitochondrial proteins are imported from the cytoplasm", "optd": "Mitochondrial proteins arise from other mitochondrial proteins", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cellular organelles are embedded in the", "opta": "endoplasmic reticulum", "optb": "cristae", "optc": "cytosol", "optd": "microtubules", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which molecule serves as a carrier of fatty acids in mitochondria?", "opta": "Acetyl-CoA", "optb": "Carnitine", "optc": "Dolichol", "optd": "Malonyl-CoA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the ester bonds of a triacylglycerol molecule's are broken then the kind of molecule, which would be soluble in water, is", "opta": "fatty acid", "optb": "steroid", "optc": "glycogen", "optd": "glycerol", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The composition of the inner mitochondrial membrane is most like that of", "opta": "the outer mitochondrial membrane", "optb": "the cell's plasma membrane", "optc": "some bacterial plasma membranes", "optd": "the nuclear membrane", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If complex III were incorporated into an artificial lipid vesicle in order to demonstrate it's proton translocating ability in isolation, which of the following would be an appropriate electron donor?", "opta": "Cytochrome c red", "optb": "Cytochrome c peroxidase", "optc": "Ubiquinol (UQH2)", "optd": "Cytochrome c oxidase", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The cell membrane is made up of", "opta": "lipoproteins", "optb": "cellulose", "optc": "phospholipids", "optd": "phosphoproteins", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements about the outer mitochondrial membrane is not true?", "opta": "The outer membrane is impermeable to hydrogen ions", "optb": "The outer membrane is highly permeable to substances of small molecular weight", "optc": "The outer membrane is about 50% lipid and 50% protein by weight", "optd": "The outer membrane contains porins", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Specialized type of peroxisome and the site of glyoxylate pathway in certain plants is known as", "opta": "gly-peroxisome", "optb": "lysosome", "optc": "glyoxysome", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following observations is not used as evidence to support the concept of endosymbiotic origin of chloroplasts and mitochondria?", "opta": "Both have their own DNA", "optb": "Both have their own ribosomes", "optc": "Both strongly resemble prokaryotes, especially in size", "optd": "Both can live and function independently of the cell", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The fluid matrix of a cell is called the", "opta": "nucleus", "optb": "cytosol", "optc": "cytoskeleton", "optd": "endoplasmic reticulum", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In plant cells, which of the following is not a function of the large central vacuoles of plant cells?", "opta": "Storage of food", "optb": "Support", "optc": "Contractile regulation of", "optd": "Waste storage water content", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following can be found as a part of the mitochondrial matrix?", "opta": "Ribosomes", "optb": "DNA", "optc": "Enzymes", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}